Guide to the Marjorie Sewell Cautley papers, 1847-1995.
Cautley, Marjorie Sewell papers, 1847-1995.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Marjorie Sewell Cautley papers, 1847-1995.
4908
Marjorie Sewell, Cautley b. 1891.
6 boxes
Family papers, including correspondence, photographs, biographical materials and 16mm.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Family papers, including correspondence and photographs from members of the Moore and Sewell families, including Judge Albert H. Sewell and Rear Admiral John White Moore; her parents William Elbridge Sewell and Minnie Sawyer Moore Sewell; and her sisters Barbara and Helen; student letters concerning her work on the Cornell University Women's Pageant and her efforts to find employment as a landscape architect. Correspondents include Ralph W. Curtis, Charles N. Lowrie, Warren J. Manning, and Russell Van Nest Black. Also, photographs, notes, and plans relating to her landscape projects including plans of Wadleigh Park (Sutton, N.H.) and Dorr's Pond (Kingston Park, Manchester, N.H.); correspondence about her hospitalization; unpublished writings by Marjorie Sewell; articles and book by her; biographical materials; and 16mm. movie films of Radburn, Sunnyside, Phipps Garden Apartments, outdoor theatres and family.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Landscape architect.
Cornell University. Class of 1917. Marjorie Sewell Cautley, the daughter of Elbridge Sewell and Minnie Moore, was born into a Navy family and spent part of her early years in Japan and Guam. She was educated at the Packer Institute for Collegiate Studies in Brooklyn, N.Y., received a B.S. in landscape architecture from Cornell University in 1917, and an M.A. in city planning from the University of Pennsylvania in 1943. After graduating from Cornell, she worked for Warren Manning in Massachusetts, and was employed by California architect Julia Morgan. She returned to New Jersey to start a private practice. In 1921 she began work on Roosevelt Common, a community park in Tenafly, NJ. She married Randolph Cautley in 1922; they were divorced in 1944. They had one daughter, Patricia Cautley Hill, born in 1925. In 1924, Marjorie S. Cautley was hired by Clarence Stein and Henry Wright, and worked on Sunnyside Gardens (1924-1928), Phipps Garden Apartments (1930, 1935), Hillside Homes (1935), and Radburn, NJ (1928-1930). She also taught site planning and landscape design as a part-time lecturer at Columbia University and at MIT. She published Garden Design in 1935 and oversaw CCC projects in New Hampshire state parks. In 1937, she was stricken with an illness that dominated the rest of her life. Although she was hospitalized for several years, she continued to write articles and completed her graduate work. Her thesis was published in part as an article in American City.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Family papers, including correspondence and photographs from members of the Moore and Sewell families, including Judge Albert H. Sewell and Rear Admiral John White Moore; her parents William Elbridge Sewell and Minnie Sawyer Moore Sewell; and her sisters Barbara and Helen; student letters concerning her work on the Cornell University Women's Pageant and her efforts to find employment as a landscape architect. Correspondents include Ralph W. Curtis, Charles N. Lowrie, Warren J. Manning, and Russell Van Nest Black. Also, photographs, notes, and plans relating to her landscape projects including plans of Wadleigh Park (Sutton, N.H.) and Dorr's Pond (Kingston Park, Manchester, N.H.); correspondence about her hospitalization; unpublished writings by Marjorie Sewell; articles and book by her; biographical materials; and 16mm. movie films of Radburn, Sunnyside, Phipps Garden Apartments, outdoor theatres and family.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cautley, Marjorie Sewell,b. 1891.; Black, Russell Van Nest, b. 1893.; Curtis, Ralph W.(Ralph Wright), 1878-1968.; Lowrie, Charles N.; Manning, Warren H.(Warren Henry), 1860-1938.; Moore family.; Moore, John White.; Sewell family.; Sewell, Albert H.; Sewell, Minnie Moore.; Sewell, William Elbridge.; Stein, Clarence S.; Walker, Nell.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University.Class of 1917.
Subjects:
Women college students.; Landscape architecture--United States.; Women landscape architects.; Parks--New Hampshire.
Places:
Hillside Homes (Bronx, New York, N.Y.)--Landscape architecture.; Sunnyside Gardens (Queens, New York, N.Y.)--Landscape architecture.; Landscape architecture--New Jersey--Radburn.; Landscape architecture--New Hampshire.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Box 1
Series II. Photographs
Box 1
Series III. Marjorie Sewell Cautley's Writings
Box 1
Series IV. Plans
Mapcase Folder 1
Series V. Geneology
Boxes 1-2, 4-6
Series VI. Films
Box 3
Series VII. Miscellaneous
Box 1
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Letters - Judge Albert Sewell, uncle & guardian of 3 Sewell girls, 1847-1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Rear Admiral John White Moore to Minne Sawyer Moore (daughter) - Letters from sea, 1883-1884 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - William Elbridge Sewell (father) and Judge Albert Sewell (uncle) - letters to Marjorie and each other, 1891-1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters to Minnie Moore Sewell to and from Elbridge Sewell (Marjorie's parents), 1893 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Elbridge from Minnie, 1892-1904 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Minnie Moore Sewell from Elbridge, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Wm. Elbridge Sewell to Louisa Moore (Aunt Lou) re: family - Marjorie Sewell at 5 years, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Birthday letter to Marjorie from Elbridge, 600 miles from Samoa, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Elbridge Sewell - letter to Marjorie from Samoa, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Judge Albert Sewell - Discussion of arrangement for Marj., Barbara, Helen Sewell; Re: arrangement for transporting Elbridge Sewell's body, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - To Mrs. Albert Sewell re: Marjorie, Barbara, and Helen Sewell, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letters to "The Girls" from Aunt Lou Moore, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Marjorie Sewell writes about her 16th birthday celebration at "Brookside", 1907 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Letters to Guam friends, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - M. L. Sewell to Dorothy Sewell (Metzger), daughter of Albert Sewell, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Emily Louisa Sawyer Moore (Mrs. John Nichols Moore), Aunt to Marjorie - Letters to M. S. C., 1913 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Marjorie - letters to her from Barbara & Helen, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Emerson, Mrs. Frances White (William) was married to Moffat - Nicknames: Ante Fran, Minnie Man, 1916-1955 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Marjorie Sewell Cornell Pageant, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Letter to Marjorie Sewell from Russell Van Nest Black, Cornell classmate. Biography - Landscape Architect, friend., 1917 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Marjorie Sewell's Cornell friends - Tracy Baldwin August, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Letter from MSC, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Invitation from the White House from President and Mrs. Wilson, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Marjorie Sewell Cautley - Roosevelt Common Tenafly, N.J., 1924 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Judge Albert Sewell to Marjorie Sewell, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Marjorie Sewell Cautley to Cornell Alumni News - Teaching at MIT; reappointment as part-time lecturer; Roosevelt Common Tenafly NJ; Hillside Housing, 1925-1935 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Writing Helen, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Letter to Pat Cautley from Robert Kohn - close friend of MSC, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Payne Whitney - Letter to Helen from Director, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Randolph Cautley to and from Russell and Mary Black re visit, also re Marjorie Cautley's condition, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Randolph Cautley re Pat Cautley (daughter) - News re MSC being at Greystone Park State Hospital, NJ for two years, 1939-1943 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Letter to Pat from MSC's cat, "Watch Out," in New Hope, PA, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Family fight over mother, 1943-1949 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Prof. Otto Faelton reccomends Marjorie Sewell to Chief Engineer at Phila. City Hall, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Wm Emerson to John Kelley, Philadelphia Housing Authority, recommends MSC to work there, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Letter from MSC to daughter Pat, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Marjorie Sewell, the last years - letters by MSC, letters from important doctors, lawyers, different institutions, 1943-1950 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Marjorie Sewell (Cautley) - letters to & from friends and relations about her illness, institutions, etc., 1944-1950+ (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Marjorie Sewell - letters to lawyers re divorce, property settlement, will, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Marjorie Sewell - illegible letter from Alcluyd Sanitarium, Berwyn, PA, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Anna Katherine Stimson to Pat Cautley Hill - Godmother & family friend, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Letter to MSC from Anna K. Stimson (best friend) (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Lucy Stimson writing to Pat Hill re MSC (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - To Pat Hill from George and Dorothy Barbour re MSC, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Letter as part of a will - 1st page missing (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Series II. Photographs
  - Elbridge Sewell, MSC's father (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Photos - MSC and Pat, The Cottage built in 1927-8, Glen Rock NJ (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Marjorie Sewell and Randolph Cautley - canoeing at Cornell U. (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Cricketts Hearth - Designed for MSC (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Cricketts Hearth, Glen Rock NJ, home of MSC, 1930s (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Rear Admiral John White Moore, grandfather of MSC (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - MSC - John White Moore, Louisa and Nem (Emily Bailey) (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Left to right: Minnie (MSC's mother), Louisa, Elsie and Emily (aunts) (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - MSC's Uncle Clarence, brother to Emily, Minnie, and Elsie (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Judge Albert Sewell family and others such as Marjorie, Barbara and Helen, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Elbridge Sewell, MSC's dad (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Minnie and Elbridge's wedding, US Navy Yard, Mare Island (originals, copies), 14 Oct 1890 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Minnie Moore and Elbridge Sewell's wedding - copies of originals (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Minnie Sawyer Moore in wedding dress and photos of MSC (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Marjorie with Mother and Father (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - MSC, 15 May 1893, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - MSC, looking forward (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Original photos of MSC as a young woman (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Fancy dress party and Lake George - MSC top row left (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Marjorie, Helen, Barbara at different ages (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Marjorie Sewell - good photos of family (leaving for Guam) etc. (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Pictures of M. Sewell & Family, Portsmouth Navy Yard, N.H. (Dorothy Sewell is daughter of MSC's uncle Judge Albert Sewell) (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - MSC - photos of her with relatives (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Elsie Moore and Marjorie (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Various photos including Marjorie Sewell (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - MSC w/3 French sailors visiting in New Hope, PA; newspaper clipping Governor of Guam, Wm. E. Sewell; family tree - enlarged (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Family pictures (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - John Nichols Moore and wife Louisa - took care of Helen, Barbara, & Marjorie, and their son John, and Robert & Horrace Mazet (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Photograph - Aunt Nem & Uncle Claude Bailey when married (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Aunt Lou - raised Marjorie and two sisters after their mother died (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Tan San, family dog, traveled w/them to Guam (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Photo of Warren Manning & grandson, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Dean William Emerson (MIT) and MSC; Frances White Emerson, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - MSC's gravestone (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - MSC's diary, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Summer photo - trip to England and Brittany - Mary Cautley, Helen Sewell, & Patsy Cautley, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Marjorie Sewell Cautley - her work (or others') on gardens and pools - some photographs by Clara E. Sipprell (Box 1, Folder 82)
- Series III. Marjorie Sewell Cautley's Writings
  - NY Newspaper, Guam's Governor (MSC's dad), 18-Oct-02 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - New York Times, Re: Elbridge Sewell's appointment as Governor of Guam - takes 3 daughters via Suez Canal, 18-Oct-02 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Marjorie Sewell - lecture at Packer Institute about Guam (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Marjorie Sewell's article on trip to Guam in 1902 - Atlantic Monthly published article in May 1913, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Re Art of Helen and Marjorie Sewell, 1920s (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Magazine Articles - originals & copies on landscaping NH parks, Radburn, Phipps Garden Apartments, 1930-1943 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Schedule of Seasons for Planting with Least Risk of Loss - Radburn, NJ, 8-Apr-30 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Schedule of Seasons for Planting with Least Risk of Loss - Radburn, NJ, 8-Apr-30 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Articles by Marjorie Sewell Cautley, 1913, 1942-3 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - MSC - article on Camoflage Planting, Apr-43 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Patt Hill re MSC, post 5/44 divorce - a reprint from Architecture (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - "The Magic of Guam," by M. Sewell, published by Atlantic Monthly (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Marjorie Sewell Cautley - magazine articles she wrote, 1934-1993 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - "MisGivings" - MSC re unhappy marriage to Randolph Cautley, probably written spring (May?), could be part of a series. (original), 1937 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Marjorie Sewell - writings about Mental Institutions etc - "Breakdown. An Anonymous Autobiography." 1942, 1930s-40s (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Marjorie Sewell - "The Black Dragon", 1940? (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Marjorie Sewell's fiction - "The Monkey Man," "Mrs. Z's Garden Party" - written in New Hope, PA period, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Miscellaneous writings, some fictitious, others true (letter to daughter Pat Cautley in pencil), 1940s (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - "Trapped" - Mental Institutions, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - "The Family Skeleton" - Sister Helen visits Marjorie in institution in the earlier years (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - "Sketches of a Mental Institution" by M. S. Cautley - NJ State Hospital, Graystone Park, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Institutional life early - "The Letter" (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Early institutional life, "The Letter" (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - "My Day Of Rest" - (Life in a cottage), 1942 (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - "Seeing Life Through A Keyhole" by MSC, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - "The Question and Parole" (poetry), 15-Jun-42 (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Marjorie Sewell, "Anonymous," mixed poems, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - M. Sewell - Writing re Mental Institutions - "Blackout the Cat", Apr-42 (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Firelight Poetry by MSC, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - "Institution", May-46 (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - "Black Out" by MSC (Box 1, Folder 113)
  - "Breaking" by MSC (Box 1, Folder 114)
  - "Futility" by MSC (Box 1, Folder 115)
  - "A Golden Opportunity" by MSC (Box 1, Folder 116)
  - "Iggy Acted Like A Lady" by MSC (Box 1, Folder 117)
  - Occupation - Graystone (Park?) State Hospital (Box 1, Folder 118)
  - "The Platform" (Box 1, Folder 119)
  - "Proper Planting" by M. Sewell (Box 1, Folder 120)
  - "Sentimental Security" by MSC (Box 1, Folder 121)
  - "The Stranger" by MSC (Box 1, Folder 122)
  - SPCA - mental institution (Box 1, Folder 123)
  - "To Die Outdoors" (Box 1, Folder 124)
  - "You Never Can Tell" by MSC (Box 1, Folder 125)
  - "Horrors of War Fail to Blunt Attractive Home Ground Desire" by MSC (Box 1, Folder 126)
- Series IV. Plans
  - Kingston Park, n.d. (Map-case Folder 1)
  - Dorrs Pond, n.d. (Map-case Folder 1)
  - Garden for John Dormer Cannon, 1934 (Map-case Folder 1)
  - Wadleigh Park, n.d. (Map-case Folder 1)
- Series V. Geneology
  - MSC's father, Commander William Elbridge Sewell: b. 16 Nov 1851, d. 17 Mar 1904, Mare Island, CA; Class of 1871 at US Naval Academy, Annapolis MD (Box 1, Folder 167)
  - Elbridge Sewell, father to MSC (Box 1, Folder 168)
  - Marjorie Louisa Sewell: Geneology 5 Aug 1891 - 16 Jul 1954 (Box 1, Folder 169)
  - Biography, by Helen Sewell (Box 1, Folder 170)
  - Biography of William Elbridge Sewell & Family - written by Barbara Sewell (middle daughter) (Guam - Minnie) (Box 1, Folder 171)
  - Family Tree (Box 1, Folder 172)
  - MSC - Family Tree (Box 1, Folder 173)
  - Uncle Claude Bailey - MSC's uncle (Box 1, Folder 174)
  - Book: "Garden Design" by Marjorie S. Cautley (Box 2)
  - House Beautiful - Article by MSC - "If We'd Only Realized", June 1937 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - House & Garden - Article by MSC, July 1937 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Marjorie Sewell Tau Sigma Delta Fraternity, University Of Pennsylvania, membership, May 31, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Marjorie Sewell - Master of Fine Arts, University Of Pennsylvania (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Chronologies 1896-1956 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Family correspondence 1873-1911 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Barabara Sewell correspondence 1909-1935 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - William E. Sewell naval orders 1871-1881 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - William E. Sewell naval orders 1882-1883 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - William E. Sewell naval orders, list of naval personnel 1885-1904 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Barbara Lee Sewell autobiographical writings: Mare Island to B. L. S. high school diploma in New Jersey [1895?]-1916 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Barbara Lee Sewell autobiographical writings (continued) 1916-1920 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Barbara Lee Sewell other writings 19-- (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Barbara Lee Sewell photographs [1985?]-1921+ (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Helen Sewell photographs 19-- (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Barbara Sewell photograph album: Sewell girls (Marjorie, Barbara, Helen) in Guam and U.S. 1899 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Barbara Sewell photograph album 1903-1907 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Miscellany 1891-1935 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Family hair clippings 1809-1913 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - W.E. Sewell Correspondence and Marriage Certificate 1899-1902, 1890 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - W.E. Sewell Financial Records 1890-1911 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Sewell Family Misc. Photos (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
  - Marjorie Sewell correspondence with parents 1899-1902 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Marjorie Sewell Cautley correspondence with friends and family 1904-1917 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Marjorie Sewell Cautley misc. correspondence 1903-1910 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Marjorie Sewell Cautley college correspondence (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Marjorie Sewell Cautley misc. correspondence and documents n.d. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Marjorie Sewell Cautley, Cornell papers 1916 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Illustrations for "Garden Design" by MSC (originals by Dirk J. Luyx) n.d. (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
  - Correspondence from Horace S. Mazet to Patricia Hill 1996 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Sewell Family Photograph 1907 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Photo Album, Lake George 1880-1890 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Photos and postcards of Asia and Lake George n.d. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Family photo album 1900 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - U.S. Naval Academy, Reunion Book, Class of 1871 1902 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Marjorie Sewell diary, Asia 1902 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Marjorie Sewell scrapbook and diary 1903-1915 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Marjorie Sewell summer camp notebook 1914 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - "Radburn Racket: The Perils of a Town Plan" by Robert D. Kohn 1929 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "Pages from an Architect's Sketchbook 1900-1930" by William Emerson 1930 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "Building a House in Sweden" by Marjorie Cautley (Illustrations by Helen Sewell) 1931 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - "The American City" magazine 1934 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Europe n.d. (Box 6, Folder 12-18)
  - Photos of Sewell girls n.d. (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Marjorie Sewell notebook n.d. (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Family Photo Album n.d. (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Munsell Book of Color n.d. (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Family Photo Album n.d. (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Series VI. Films
  - Film in box: "Roads" - M. Sewell, c/o Russell Black, New Hope, PA (Box 3)
    Available on DVD #19 Chapter 1 ? Shows bulding with sign that states "Woman's Club" [sic].
  - Film in box: "Personal/Children" - M. Sewell, c/o Russell Black, New Hope, PA (Box 3)
    Available on DVD #19 Chapter 2
  - Film in box: "Sunnyside" - M. Sewell, c/o Russell Black, New Hope, PA (Box 3)
    Available on DVD #19 Chapter 3
  - Film reel: New Hope, PA - M. Sewell, L.A., The Tenafly Outdoor Theatre, Cinderella played by high school students. Also The Roosevelt Memorial presented by Malcolm S. Mackay (Box 3)
    Available on DVD #19 Chapter 4
  - Film reel: New Hope, PA - M. Sewell, L.A., Phipps Garden Apartments, Long Island City N.Y., Tree planting, Sunnyside. (Box 3)
    Available on DVD #19 Chapter 5
  - Film reel: Radburn, NJ - 16mm film by Marjorie Sewell Cautley (Box 3)
    Available on DVD #19 Chapter 6 and VHS Video #193.
  - Film in box: "?" - M. Sewell, c/o Russell Black, New Hope, PA (Box 3)
    Not on DVD?
- Series VII. Miscellaneous
  - Important miscellaneous documents, 1891-1955 (Box 1, Folder 127)
  - Camp: Invitation for older girls, Lake George NY - MSC director (Box 1, Folder 128)
  - MSC personal childhood drawings (Box 1, Folder 129)
  - Marjorie Sewell: her watercolor sketches of Guam and copies of them, 1903-1905 (Box 1, Folder 130)
  - Pratt Institute Courses, 1915-1916 (Box 1, Folder 131)
  - Marjorie Sewell's Cornell U. entrance papers, grades etc. and bills, Sept. 1915 (Box 1, Folder 132)
  - American Society of Landscape Architects - Membership List, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 133)
  - Helen Spaulding Phipps, Class of 1916, a best friend of Marjorie Sewell (Box 1, Folder 134)
  - Receipts of MSC for pageant, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 135)
  - Marjorie Sewell - Copies of job applications and answers (Spring) sent when graduating from Cornell. Pageant, Warren Manning, Russell Van Nest Black, etc., 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 136)
  - Responses to 1917 Job Applications (originals), 1917 (Box 1, Folder 137)
  - "Country Life" Magazine. Charles E. Cutler, Architect; Helen Sewell, Sketches; Marjorie Sewell Cautley, Landscape Architect, Aug-22 (Box 1, Folder 138)
  - Marjorie Sewell - Professional Services for Mrs. S. L. Stix, 4-Dec-23 (Box 1, Folder 139)
  - Marjorie Sewell Cautley - writings in regard to Helen Sewell's work, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 140)
  - Phipps Garden Apartments - Maintenance IV of Planting, 27-Apr-32 (Box 1, Folder 141)
  - Publicity for lectures - garden clubs, schools etc, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 142)
  - Flyers on illustrated lectures she will give (from Cornell U.'s Carl A. Kroch Library), Aug-35 (Box 1, Folder 143)
  - Masters Degree, school of Fine Arts - photo of model of slum clearance, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 144)
  - Marjorie Sewell Cautley vs Randolph Vivian Cautley - Divorce Document 14 April 1944, Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 145)
  - Records of proceeds of sale of two Hawthorne NJ Homes (Box 1, Folder 146)
  - USS Supply Stationary - Xmas Card by MSC (Box 1, Folder 147)
  - Pioneers of American Landscape Design, pages 23-24, for Cornell Universitt (Box 1, Folder 148)
  - Misc Info MSC (Box 1, Folder 149)
  - Marjorie S. Cautley School Records: Packer Institute, Cornell University, University of Pennsylvania, etc. Professional listings and Nell Walker's commentary, 1917 on (Box 1, Folder 150)
  - Cornell University, Marjorie Sewell (Cautley), Alumni Information Office (Box 1, Folder 151)
  - William Emerson, professional comments re Marjorie Sewell Cautley, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 152)
  - Exhibit 20 Jan 1985, Wave Hill - Exhibit of American Gardens & Landscapes on Paper, Marjorie Cautley's "Redburn Gardens", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 153)
  - Radcliffe Exhibit includes MSC's work, 6-May-93 (Box 1, Folder 154)